Finding Aid for Preston W. Slosson papers, 1918-1952
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Preston W. Slosson papers 1918-1952
Slosson, Preston W. (Preston William), 1892-
1 linear foot
865 Aa 2
Professor history at the University of Michigan; files relating to his work with the American Commission to Negotiate Peace, 1918-1919, and as a radio broadcaster commenting on world events during the Second World War.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The collection was donated by Professor Slosson (donor no. 778 ). The American Commission to Negotiate Peace files came from Professor Howard Ehrmann (donor no. 2721 ) in 1965. The photographs were given by Mike Church (donor no. 2313 ).
The collection is open to research.
Preston Slosson was born in Laramie, Wyoming on September 2, 1892. He received his Ph.D in history from Columbia University in 1916. He was Literary Editor of the New York Independent in 1917, then went to work in the US State Department as an assistant librarian with the American Commission to Negotiate Peace, 1917-1919. He returned to New York Independent from 1920 to 1921, then came to Ann Arbor as an instructor in history with a specialty in modern European history. He became full professor in 1937, teaching there until his retirement in1962. During World War II, Slosson made radio broadcasts on WWJ in Detroit entitled "Slosson Interprets the News."
The collection covers but a small portion of Preston Slosson's career: his work as staff member with the American Commission to Negotiate Peace following World War I and the radio broadcasts he made from 1940 to 1947 in which he discussed the news from the perspective of history. The remainder of the collection includes letters from his travels and family. The collection does not document his career as a history teacher, his candidacy for the US Congress in 1948, or his various organization activities.
Subjects:
American Commission to Negotiate the Peace.; Clergy--Wyoming.; Congregational Churches--Wyoming.; League of Nations.; Radio broadcasting--United States.; Samoan Islands; Treaty of Versailles (1919); United States--Politics and government--1933-1953.; University of Michigan. Dept. of History.; University of Michigan--Faculty.; Voyages and travels.; Wyoming.; Slosson, Preston W. (Preston William), 1892-
Subjects - Visual Materials:
Slosson, Preston W. (Preston William), 1892-
Genre Terms:
Photographs.
- American Commission to Negotiate Peace, 1917-1919
  - Czechoslovakian boundary discussions, 1919 (Box 1)
  - Polish boundary discussions, 1919 and 1931 (Box 1)
  - Labor conditions (Box 1)
  - Treaties with Poland, Czechoslovakia, and Roumania (Box 1)
  - Reparations provisions (Box 1)
  - Re. ports, waterways and railroads, and on penalties against Germany (Box 1)
  - Disarmament of Germany and the political disposition of Alsace-Lorraine (Box 1)
  - Shantung, 1919 (Box 1)
  - Inquiry paper entitled, "The Diplomatic History of the Kingdom of Samoa" October 1918 (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 1)
- Speeches and addresses
  - Speech, "Europe Takes the Plunge" October 12, 1939 (Box 1)
  - Radio addresses, undated and January 1940-February 8, 1947, 27 folders (Box 1)
  - Correspondence concerning radio addresses, 1942-1943 (Box 1)
- Other papers
  - Correspondence, 1930 (Box 1)
    (include letters in German from Heinz von Paller)
  - Later correspondence, 1970s (Box 1)
  - Travel letters (mimeographed)
    - Trip to England, 1938-1939 (Box 1)
    - Trip to western United States, 1940 (Box 1)
  - Family letters (mimeographed) (Box 1)
  - Letters from family members (include Flora May Slosson Wuellner, Congregational pastor in Wyoming) (Box 1)
  - Slosson's notes on course taught by James T. Shotwell at Columbia entitled "Outline of English Industrial History (156) (Box 1)
  - History 11-12 (observations on), 1952 (Box 1)
  - Rollins College Conference on World Government
    - Proceedings, March 11-16, 1946 (Box 1)
    - "A Short Summary of Some Recent Suggestions on International Organization" (Box 1)
  - Photographs (Portraits) (Box 1)